Guide to the Lionel Stevenson Papers, 1808-1989, bulk 1911-1974 UA.29.02.0014
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Organizations, 3 boxes
  - A - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - B - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - C - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - D - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - E - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - I - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - L - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - M - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - O - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - P - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - S - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - T-U - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - W - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - Y - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
- Manuscripts and Notes, .25 boxes
  - Loose Pages of Untitled Manuscript (Box 11)
  - Incomplete Manuscript (Box 11)
  - The Renaissance: Studies in Art and Poetry (Box 11)
  - Revolt Among the Artists (1 of 4) (Box 11)
  - Revolt Among the Artists (2 of 4) (Box 11)
  - Revolt Among the Artists (3 of 4) (Box 11)
  - Revolt Among the Artists (4 of 4) (Box 11)
  - The Verse Writers Book (Box 11)
- Clippings, .5 boxes
  - Articles and Reviews of Dr. Quicksilver (Box 11)
  - Articles and Reviews of Darwin Among the Poets (Box 11)
  - Articles and Reviews of The Wild Irish Girl (Box 11)
  - Bliss Carmen (Box 11)
  - A (Box 11)
  - B (Box 11)
  - C (Box 11)
  - D (Box 11)
  - H (Box 11)
  - K (Box 11)
  - L (Box 11)
  - M (Box 11)
  - N-O (Box 11)
  - P (Box 11)
  - R (Box 11)
  - S (Box 11)
  - T-U (Box 11)
  - W (Box 11)
  - Y (Box 11)
  - Smythe, Albert E. S. (Box 11)
  - 1933-1938 (Box 11)
  - 1939-1946 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous (1 of 2) (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous (2 of 2) (Box 11)
  - Poems (Box 11)
- Diaries, 1919-1974; 2 boxes
  - 1919-1950 (Box 12)
  - 1951-1974 (Box 13)
- Oversized Materials, 4 boxes
  - Autograph Collection, 1808-1946 (Box 14)
  - Authors Club (Box 14)
  - English Speaking Union (Box 14)
  - Clippings
    - Articles and Reviews of Showman of Vanity Fair (Box 14)
    - Authors Club (Box 14)
    - Chaparral Horizons and Chaparral Voices (Box 14)
    - English 290 - Cross-Currents in English, French, and American Cultures (Box 14)
    - Joyce Cary (Box 14)
    - Re: Activities of Lionel Stevenson (Box 14)
    - Re: Biographical Information (Box 14)
    - Re: Family, Friends, and Canadian Poets and Authors (Box 14)
    - Re: The Ordeal of George Meredith, 1953 (Box 14)
  - Scrapbook: News Cuttings, 1914-1920 (Box 15)
    Scope and Contents note
    Clippings are poems and essays written by Lionel Stevenson from age 12 to 18.
  - Scrapbook: 1899-1917 (Box 15)
    Scrapbook is very fragile.
  - Poster - Lionel Stevenson Essay Contest, 1977 (Box 15)
  - Book: Joyce Cary Remembered (Box 15)
  - Audio Cassette, 1973 (Box 15)
    Tape recording by Lionel Stevenson concerning the history of his native region of Canada.
  - Scrapbook of Clippings, ca. 1898-1915 (Box 16)
- Canadiana, 1 box
  Papers and Magazines regarding Canadian history.
  - The Lionel Stevenson Collection of Canadiana (Box 17)
  - Maclean's: Canada's National Magazine, July 27, 1963 (Box 17)
  - The Chatelaine: A Magazine for Canadian Women, March, 1929 (1 of 2) (Box 17)
  - The Chatelaine: A Magazine for Canadian Women, March, 1929 (2 of 2) (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings and Newsletters (Box 17)
- Oversized Artwork
  Items were previously housed in the general oversize collection.
  - Photograph of the 88th Battalion, Canadian Fusiliers, Esquimalt, British Columbia, 1914, before sailing for war, mounted 8X10. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Cornelius Krieghoff, Biographical Sketch, reproductions of paintings, Canadian art. (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Reproductions of Paintings of Paul Coran. (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - F.C. Hill, watercolor (5.25X9.25) of Union Bay Vancouver. (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Canadian Art, Reproductions of Paintings, various artists. (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Don Blanding, Photograph (Autographed) and design (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - F.C. Hill, watercolor (6.5X9.75), Qualicum Bay, Vancouver Island, 1913. (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - M.P. Judge, watercolors (9.5X7.5) and 3 (3.75X5.75), scenes of British Columbia. (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Reproductions of works by M. Cullen and E. Rarzic, 4 (11x8.5) (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Gardner and Brietzcke, pictures of a wood engraving by Briscombe Gardner, a letter from Edmund Henry Brietzcke to Dr. Lionel Stevenson and The Great and the Small, a chart of miscellaneous scientific facts copyrighted by Brietzcke. (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Martha Louise Black (Mrs. George Black) prints of their works, 2 postcard reproductions, 1 autographed. (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Wilson MacDonald (Canadian poet, 1880-1967) (Box 18)
    Biographical Sketch, one hand decorated poem and two printed poems.